<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>apeirotope - life</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/atom/life.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2019-05-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>the urgency of slowness</title><link href="/life/2019-05-19-the-urgency-of-slowness.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>corcra</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-05-19:/life/2019-05-19-the-urgency-of-slowness.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My parents are not originally from Dublin. My father came to Ireland from Chile in the 70s, and my mother came from Wicklow a bit later. In both cases the rest of their family stayed behind for the most part, so visiting family has always meant travelling. My family regularly …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My parents are not originally from Dublin. My father came to Ireland from Chile in the 70s, and my mother came from Wicklow a bit later. In both cases the rest of their family stayed behind for the most part, so visiting family has always meant travelling. My family regularly made the 18-odd hour journey from Dublin to Santiago during my youth. I've since learned that regular transcontinental travel is not the norm, and you don't get free food on short-haul flights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Driving down to Wicklow we used to pass through the Glen of the Downs. In the Glen, environmental and political activists demonstrated in the forest and painted messages on the wall overlooking the valley. I grew up wanting to be an eco-warrior like them. I wanted to live in a tree in the hills, with a valley to protect. Along the way I forgot about living in a tree and I got caught up in normal life, a life lived safely within the boundaries of social acceptability. Only once have I appeared on television during a protest about anything. In the light of the (semi-)recent IPCC report about the increasingly catastrophic outlook for the planet's climate, I wonder if I and others like me will be looked back at with scorn. Scorn for our inaction, our unwillingness to sacrifice anything, our complacency in the face of unfolding disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try not to be complacent. In the calculus of personal responsibility for climate change, I think I fare better than others in my situation. I'm going on 8 and a half years of vegetarianism. I don't drive: I don't actually know how to drive. Privileged as I am to live in cities, I cycle, walk, or take public transport everywhere. I donate to environmental charities. I don't buy new things very often, I avoid plastic. Every time I brush my teeth, every time I wash dishes, I think about water conservation. I don't leave the light on. I hang my clothes out to dry. But I am still a (north-western) European, and I'm well-off. The comforts of my life come at a premium that I will barely have to pay. I take warm showers, I enjoy continuous electricity and high-end consumer devices. And I fly. A lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June of 2013, I thought of myself as well-travelled. I had been to Chile countless times; once to Easter Island, and another time to the Atacama desert. I had been to California and Florida, Turkey and Vietnam. When I decided to move to the USA for a PhD I knew it was a more serious kind of emigration than moving to England had been. But at the time I had not deeply thought about being a scientist as well as an emigrant. Between conference travel and visiting home and family in Europe, over those 5.4 years my propensity for air travel increased precipitously. I started writing this en route to South Africa in January 2019 (it's been in the outbox for a while). Between November 2018 and February 2019 I will have been in Zurich (home), San Francisco, New York, Montreal (via Geneva), Dublin (other home), London, Cape Town (via Johannesburg, Paris, George, and Amsterdam), and Mexico City. That's four transcontinental trips in as many months. This would have been unthinkable to a teenage version of myself. One acclimates quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that flying is very convenient. Flying is unbelievably fast. Flying allows you to convert money into time, in what is so obviously an excellent trade that anyone with the means would surely be foolish to turn it down. This speed opens up the possibility of spending the weekend in another country and returning for work as usual on Monday. Going to the other side of the planet becomes inconvenient only because 12 hours on a plane can become uncomfortable. The entertainment system might stop working, the crying of a child may interrupt already fitful sleep at 35,000 feet, and the food may be bland or unrecognisable. The idea that air travel is damaging in some abstract way to the environment does not practically feature into the considerations one makes around time, money, layovers, legroom, screaming children, discarded water bottles, city views, packing. There is a sense that flying might be contributing somehow to climate change, but for an extra 10 euro you can offset your carbon, and climate change is sort of not obviously happening right now, and there's still some time left, and anyway it's those top 100 companies that are really causing it, so it's probably fine. You move on to seat selection: windows are good for long trips because you can lean against the wall, but what if you want to go to the bathroom?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the winter of 2018 I finally got to take the "Adirondack" between Montreal and New York. This is a passenger train route which travels through the Hudson valley and the Adirondack mountains, and it takes about 11 hours end to end. I had previously thought about it in 2015 when I was still living in New York and Montreal was hosting a popular conference in my field. In the end I decided I couldn't afford to add two days of travel to the trip, even if those days could be spent preparing for the conference. I figured any such train-based preparation would be inferior to what I could do from my office, so the most efficient solution would be to minimise travel time. Besides, the money wasn't mine, and everyone else was flying. In December 2018 the conference came back to Montreal, and my PhD defense required me to return to New York, so I killed two non-metaphorical endangered species with one stone and made the transatlantic trip. This time, when the opportunity arose, I took the train.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not a stranger to long rail journeys. Like many middle-class Europeans, I spent one intense summer travelling our small continent on trains of varying speed and quality. These at-times ten-hour journeys were spent eating illicit sandwiches smuggled from hostel breakfasts, debating still-intractable philosophical positions, and otherwise smoothly blurring into the rest of the trip. So I was not worried - I knew I could entertain myself, even without friends on hand to practice Hungarian with. We left Montreal at 10am and arrived in New York's Penn station after 9pm. Over eleven hours I watched the landscape change almost imperceptibly slowly. The urban area of Montreal slipped away as the snow receded. Frozen lakes cracked and melted, and bare trees gave way to the distant brown-green valleys of Vermont. I saw tree swings and tree houses and a pair of wooden chairs on a hill overlooking the river. I thought about life in these places. I speculated. After five years under the abstract sense of panic I attribute to doing a PhD, I basked in the luxury of time. For eleven hours, I didn't really do anything. I didn't try to pass the time, nor did I clamour to use it. I sat, mostly, gazing out the window as the sun moved across the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choosing to fly is a complex decision. Due to economic and political forces I have yet to understand, it's often the cheaper option, and not everyone has the same abundance of time as an academic who just finished her PhD, nor the same willingness to spend ten hours looking at variations on wintry landscapes. I can't ask people to stop flying, I wouldn't even ask it of myself. But I have come to realise that the idea that flying turns money into time is an elaborate self-deception. You can't buy time. You can only (if you are lucky) choose how to spend it. Spending it in paradoxically-monotonous bursts of speed seems to be the default choice for anyone with the money and the inclination. It was for me, but I'm done. I'm done with priding myself on my tolerance for complicated itineraries, I'm done with "at least you can watch movies!", with habitually storing my toiletries in a plastic bag. I'm done with finding the view above the clouds unremarkable. I'm done with the urgency of flying, the devaluation of time spent doing little. I'm done with a culture of treating environmental issues as sources of guilt and little else, a carbon offset to be purchased, and a hope that everything will get better by someone else's hand. Moving slowly might not save the world, but at least I'll see the trees while they last.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="environment"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="phd"></category><category term="trains"></category></entry><entry><title>roller derby week 4</title><link href="/life/2016-09-29-roller-derby-4.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-09-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>corcra</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-09-29:/life/2016-09-29-roller-derby-4.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See week 3 &lt;a href="/life/2016-09-24-roller-derby-3.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It had occurred to me that I might injure myself while practising, and I had thought about avoiding practising on the weekends to give myself time to heal before Monday. I think about a lot of things that don't happen. So having somehow intensified the the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See week 3 &lt;a href="/life/2016-09-24-roller-derby-3.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It had occurred to me that I might injure myself while practising, and I had thought about avoiding practising on the weekends to give myself time to heal before Monday. I think about a lot of things that don't happen. So having somehow intensified the the bruise on my thigh on Sunday afternoon, I spent Monday afternoon trying to talk myself out of goinng to training. On one hand, my body was &lt;em&gt;fine&lt;/em&gt;... everywhere except the bruise. On the other hand, even light touches against the bruise were bafflingly painful. On another part of the second hand, apparently that place is where I fall, and apparently falling is a thing I do. I consulted the internet on the consequences of bruising already-bruised skin and it told me I have cancer, so I went back pensively writing SQL queries while waiting for the subconscious to figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I printed off the &lt;a href="https://wftda.com/rules"&gt;rules of flat track roller derby&lt;/a&gt; and went to training, where I sat solemnly in the centre of the track, huddled in my antiquated Pirate Party hoodie, gazing jealously at the rest of the newbies. I figured, even if I'm not skating, I can learn something by watching and listening. &lt;em&gt;Or&lt;/em&gt;, instead of watching and listening, I could continue to deliberate about joining in, while slowly succumbing to the clammy sense of inadequacy inspired by watching other people get better while I sit on my partially-broken ass shivering like an abandoned dog. I stand by my decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They covered backwards skating, transitions (switching between forward and backwards skating), and derby stops. A derby stop is roughly when you turn around to use your toe stops to stop (in quad skates, the rubber stop thing is on the &lt;em&gt;front&lt;/em&gt; of the shoe, as opposed to the back on inline skates). I just went looking for an illustrative gif and fell into a hole of roller derby gifs followed by kentucky derby puppy gifs, so I offer no further explanation of derby stops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transitions are worrying for me, because one approach (the simpler/easier one, possibly) is to do a mohawk turn. This amounts to briefly going into first or second position in ballet, where your feet form a line with toes pointing outwards. I have &lt;em&gt;really tight&lt;/em&gt; hips, which has not served me well through many hours of ballet and yoga (I can't sit cross-legged, to the confusion of many), so achieving that position with my feet takes time and hurts. I have yet to properly learn transitions (I have yet to properly learn skating backwards), but so far I have been using a weird combination of multi-step-hops and spinning on my toes to turn around. Time will tell if these are acceptable methods, cause I don't see mohawk turns happening any time soon. Maybe I'll skip that part and go straight to jumping 180 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later that week, something bizarre happened. Deflated after sitting out of training, and struggling to pull myself out of silver league in Overwatch, I tried some very casual, very careful derby practice at home. My room is small and the rest of the house contains far too many breakable objects to practice in, so home-practice consists of putting my skates on and then rolling carefully back and forth between my computer desk and my wardrobe. One day I will stream myself skating around my room while waiting to respawn in Overwatch, and it will be beautiful and terrible. The bizarre thing was that when I put my skates on, instead of my body seizing up in terror, I continued to feel like a normal person capable of controlling my legs. That is when I discovered I could spin on my front wheels. Had I always felt like this? Was the fear a strange dream? Had I actually found it difficult to do side lunges before? Was I suffering from some temporary bruise-induced delusion? I honestly don't know what happened. It is unsurprising that I would become more comfortable with practice, but I didn't expect it to be a step function. That's not to say that I feel entirely comfortable on skates (&lt;em&gt;lord&lt;/em&gt; no), but it seems my fear is now focused on new things (like transitions and crossovers), instead of &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gear talk interlude: The 'newbie' skates I bought are Riedell R3s, which come with PowerDyne (round, adjustable) toe stops. It turns out that these are on the smaller end for toe stops, so balancing on them is a &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt; like balancing on high heels (except, you know, on the toe). Natalie has voiced concerns about twisting her ankle while trying to do a derby stop with these, so we are going to order bigger toe stops, most likely Gumballs. Hobbies: never not incurring costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday we found a carpark by Zurich airport for practice. It was a &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt; too inclined for me to feel happy doing much more than intensely failing at slalom, but I also took some time to explain crossover mechanics to Natalie. I can &lt;em&gt;understand&lt;/em&gt; things without being able to &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; them, a fact which is persistently frustrating. Part of this explanation involved me standing mostly-still and crossing one foot over the other, which is not a thing I thought I could do. In fact, that is a thing which I explicitly said I couldn't do &lt;a href="/life/2016-09-15-roller-derby-2.html"&gt;two weeks earlier&lt;/a&gt;, so I was astonished and smug in equal measure for the rest of the day. Also a wizard. I have a quiet confidence that I could do crossovers if I tried now, but at the time of writing, I've had The Bruise for almost three weeks and it's &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; there and &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; (somewhat) painful. During the earlier gif tangent I found a catalogue of derby bruises, which begs the question: how is everyone's first bruise so goddamn &lt;em&gt;small&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="roller derby"></category></entry><entry><title>roller derby week 3</title><link href="/life/2016-09-24-roller-derby-3.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-09-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>corcra</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-09-24:/life/2016-09-24-roller-derby-3.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See week 2 &lt;a href="/life/2016-09-15-roller-derby-2.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having discovered and then fixed an embarassingly serious bug in my code on Friday, I spent the weekend before the paper deadline at the office rerunning experiments. This is a slow process - for whatever reason, tensorflow takes several minutes to fully initialise the computation graph for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See week 2 &lt;a href="/life/2016-09-15-roller-derby-2.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having discovered and then fixed an embarassingly serious bug in my code on Friday, I spent the weekend before the paper deadline at the office rerunning experiments. This is a slow process - for whatever reason, tensorflow takes several minutes to fully initialise the computation graph for my experiments, so there's a decent lag before even first results start coming out. Delays like this are frustrating because they're too long to spend staring at the screen or otherwise doing nothing, yet too short to properly do anything else. Sure, I could practice mindfulness meditation or skim abstracts or read emails or temporarily intensify the attention I am paying to the Hamilton soundtrack constantly playing in the background, but I am a human and I have limits. That weekend, I capitalised on the solitude of a Swiss office on a Sunday to practice some skating. That means putting on all my gear, sitting quietly at my desk typing, and then doing laps up and down the corridor while tensorflow backpropagates through time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The corridor is long and smooth and mostly empty, but it's not especially &lt;em&gt;wide&lt;/em&gt;, so corners and crossovers and such were out of the question. I skated up and down and bumped gracelessly into walls on either end and then I somehow, just, sort of &lt;em&gt;got&lt;/em&gt; stickyfeet. What had been demanding and somehow counterproductive became obvious and natural. What did I figure out? Physical actions are hard to explain, but here goes. It has to do with the distribution of weight/balance on the different wheels. So the situation with basic stickyfeet is that you're keeping both skates on the ground, but propelling yourself forward by moving your legs 'out', while your toes point out a bit (if your toes point in, you go backwards and then die). But it's not just 'move your legs out'. &lt;em&gt;For me&lt;/em&gt;, it seems that I need to release some weight from my &lt;em&gt;front&lt;/em&gt; wheels to facilitate the forward moving. I asked Natalie and she thought it might be outer/inner wheels, so maybe mileage varies here. Whatever it is, I'm pretty sure the DerbyNoob Stance of attempting to cling to the ground through one's skates is directly in opposition to the kind of subtle balance shifts required to actually do anything beyond scrabble desperately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also did a bit of backwards stickyfeet-skating, because the movement is the same, just reversed somehow. If I thought I would have been skating backwards (for some definition of skating - I am bad at backwards) within a month of putting skates on, I would not have believed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In class week three, we did:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;slalom: This is something from skiing, I think? I did cross-country skiing once. When I was growing up, skiing was the domain of private school kids and my family in Chile. In derby it's weaving between cones. Current status: nah, not really, nope. I just can't turn that tightly. I tried weaving between every &lt;em&gt;second&lt;/em&gt; cone and that was almost possible. However, bizarrely, later in the class we had to weave between skaters and I could do that. Maybe staring at cones on the ground makes skating harder. Maybe I'm just afraid of cones. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hopping: I mentioned in &lt;a href="/life/2016-08-28-roller-derby-0.html"&gt;week 0&lt;/a&gt; that I'm able to jump on the surface at the gym. This is true. You know what happens when I jump on other surfaces? I'd upload a picture of The Bruise but it's on that part of the leg where ass becomes thigh, the part of the leg you can't just display unless you're at a beach or in a sexually liberated society. The forbidden leg zone. Let me give myself some credit here. We had to jump over a small pile of cones (&lt;em&gt;cones&lt;/em&gt;, you mysterious bastards). My initial reaction was "no, hell no, jesus no" but then I remembered that all is meaningless and came to peace with the jumble of bones and gristle that would soon constitute my body, and I gave it a go. The first few times I basically just landed too hard on the front wheels and kept going, either hitting my toe stops or falling on my knees. A goldilocks siuation was afoot - that was too much front, so I overcompensated the next time and went too much back. Instead of getting eaten by bears or whatever it is that happened to goldilocks, I landed on my back wheels and fell arms-flailingly backwards onto my thigh. Apparently my left upper thigh is just where I fall. I think I crawled off the track and climbed onto a chair, because the initial impact caused my leg to go various kinds of numb. The resulting bruise was mysteriously round and violently purple, probably about eight cm in diameter. More on this later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;focus: this was really fun. We assembled a pack (roughly, 'be within arms distance of two people at all times') and then had to skate around while identifying colours and numbers from various teachers/refs who were possibly behind us. Apparently I skate better when I am slightly distracted. I am reminded of a cognitive test I had done some years earlier at the &lt;a href="https://dublin.sciencegallery.com/"&gt;Science Gallery&lt;/a&gt; where I had to memorise numbers said aloud while also solving a maze puzzle. They tested both tasks independently and then together, and I did better doing both at once. My explanation for this is that while free to either look or listen (i.e. no maze or no numbers) I got distracted by things in the environment (this was happening in a fairly busy room) which broke my concentration, whereas doing both at once required focus but not in a way that excluded my capacity at the other task. Another example: I find it very helpful to draw/doodle/fidget while listening to things, but unfortunately that comes across badly in meetings. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another amazing thing during the class was that I did a crossover. How? Well, I just... sort of... did it. I had been trying to first practice crossing my feet over while standing still, or skating on one foot, or whatever. But then one of the teachers was like 'just try it' and I was probably already delirious from all the blood pooling in my thigh so I went for it, and it happened, and everything was beautiful and nothing hurt. And then I fell on my knees, but I think that's because I had no end-game for the move. I assumed I would try and fall, so once I wasn't falling I didn't know where to go, and I fell. So a holy grail (there are many) of skating seemed within reach. I had done it once, and I could - in theory - do it again. So that Sunday, after The Bruise had recovered enough that I could walk mostly normally again, I hit the gym.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insert a wheel-switching montage here. Did I mention I ordered bearings for the new wheels, to make switching easier? And I forgot how to do numbers, so I got half as many as I needed? Masters degree in mathematics right here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been at the gym for about twenty minutes when it happened. I had skated in circles, I had skidded weirdly on stripes on the floor (it's one of those multipurpose courts covered in every sports marking), and then I went for the crossover. And I fell. straight. onto. the. bruise. I wanted to yell at everyone and no one in particular that I already had a bruise there, that I already had a massive, deep bruise, so they would not judge me for crawling back to the bench, trying not to cry. It hurt, it hurt so bad and I felt repulsed and yet obsessed by the idea of pressing on that mess of blood and broken veins. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sat on the bench and breathed deliberately, waiting for the waves of pain and dizzying shock to subside, psyching myself up to try &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt; because I was so determined to get this, and then a man appeared. He was not in sports attire. He did not have a smiling face. He communicated in limited English that rollerblading is not permitted in the hall. I asked if there was somewhere else I could go. He said no. I asked again and he said he would get someone who spoke better English. He retrieved one of the basketball players who had been in the hall beside me. The basketball player told me that skating was not allowed. The skates would damage the surface. I asked if there was somewhere else I could practice. He said no. I nodded. I thanked the men. I ripped off my knee pads and elbow pads and wrist pads. I took off my skates. I looked at the pile of gear sitting beside me. I looked at the changing room door on the far side of the hall. I tried to shove my gear into my helmet and it didn't fit, so I put my helmet on and grabbed the shoes by the laces and looped my keys around a finger as I held my bottle under my arm, knee pads cupping the shoulder pads, the skates getting heavier as I left sweaty footprints on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="roller derby"></category><category term="tensorflow"></category></entry><entry><title>roller derby week 2ish</title><link href="/life/2016-09-15-roller-derby-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-09-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>corcra</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-09-15:/life/2016-09-15-roller-derby-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See week 1 &lt;a href="/life/2016-08-29-roller-derby-1.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I endeavoured to revise and presumably master all the material we covered in the first class on a Sunday afternoon (nerd, remember. Historically 'Good At School'). It seemed quite straight forward. I would just repeat the difficult thing until it became easy. I've been there. I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See week 1 &lt;a href="/life/2016-08-29-roller-derby-1.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I endeavoured to revise and presumably master all the material we covered in the first class on a Sunday afternoon (nerd, remember. Historically 'Good At School'). It seemed quite straight forward. I would just repeat the difficult thing until it became easy. I've been there. I used to spend an hour a day &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; playing scales on my violin. Repetition is the key to mastery. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I failed to account for the fact that in physical activities, mistakes aren't free. They hurt. They can damage you. I'm writing this three and a half weeks after the failed T-stop at the first training, and my ankle still hurts. So when I put my gear on and stood up in the sports hall, instead of taking off with the casually intense focus of one committed to a task, I became very aware of how precarious my situation was. It seemed likely if not utterly predetermined that I would fall, badly, onto my back - maybe twisting my legs or ankles as I went down, or falling onto an arm and breaking it, implausibly - my wrists were too well protected but - presumably the forearm can break somehow - can you break elbows? This in mind, my plans of mastery withered to a single hope - to survive unscathed, and maybe be a bit less terrified in an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remembering the almost-comically predictable 'falling at the corners' I'd done at training, I managed to expand my rapidly-contracting ambition for the day to include learning how to turn. Because the gym is only available for a few hours on Sundays, I first went home and watched a lot of youtube videos (some relevant) and thought about acceleration, broadly defined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is what I learned: you can turn by pushing the outer foot out. You lean a bit into the turn, putting weight on the inner leg, and push the outer foot roughly 'outwards' (actual trajectory is more like a curve since you're moving forwards at the same time). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I realised this - in the sense of actually &lt;em&gt;achieving&lt;/em&gt; it, rather than understanding it conceptually (which was easy), I felt so accomplished I almost forgot how wildly I had moved the goalposts on my afternoon to get there. I got excited for the prospect of trying the '27 in 5' again, because the secret to turning corners without losing &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; my speed had been unlocked and maybe I'd get a score I could say in public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I almost missed training session two, because I spent most of the day in a haze of pain and sickness, semi-conscious and clawing pitifully in the direction of Netflix. Scientist was baffled. I made a deal with myself where I would go via tram (as opposed to bike - not a fan of cycling when I'm dizzy) and take breaks as often as necessary. Probably not a good health choice, probably don't take health advice from me... or definitely &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt;, because I miraculously got better, and it was certainly due to roller derby and not the extended nap I took in the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlights of the class included me seeing side planks with leg lifts, thinking 'I can probably do this, I have done this before', and being &lt;em&gt;totally incapable&lt;/em&gt; of lifting my legs, because that's what happens when you add a 2kg (?) weight to the end of your leg and also stop going to yoga six months earlier. We also did some 'agility', which involved things like balancing on one skate (I was pretty good at this - I have good balance), jumping to the side (somehow easier than it sounds), and stepping to the side while crossing one foot over the other (&lt;em&gt;LITERALLY IMPOSSIBLE&lt;/em&gt;, anyone who can do this is a &lt;em&gt;WIZARD&lt;/em&gt;). We also did a pattern of zig-zagging around the track (cutting from side to side) which exceeded my limited ability to do sticky feet (skating without lifting your feet) and involved a lot of baleful middle-distance stares as I rolled unceremoniously to a stop. But I barely fell, and someone said it looked like I had been practicing, so I left the place wearing the invisible sunglasses of a person inwardly giddy with pride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was then travelling for rougly a week while trying to finish and submit a paper, so I missed the next training - but it was actually an intro to the extensive rules of roller derby, which I have already largely ready (nerd, remember), so the exhilirating story of learning-to-skate continues uninterrupted whenever I write the next one of these. Right now I have to find a sleeping position that doesn't involve the bruised side of my body.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="roller derby"></category></entry><entry><title>roller derby week 1</title><link href="/life/2016-08-29-roller-derby-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-08-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>corcra</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-08-29:/life/2016-08-29-roller-derby-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See week 0 &lt;a href="/life/2016-08-28-roller-derby-0.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a nerd. I didn't want to go to class &lt;em&gt;unprepared&lt;/em&gt;, so a few weeks before the Rookie Course started, I went to a neighbouring canton to buy derby gear so I could practice. Practice and hope to attain a minimal competency such that I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See week 0 &lt;a href="/life/2016-08-28-roller-derby-0.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a nerd. I didn't want to go to class &lt;em&gt;unprepared&lt;/em&gt;, so a few weeks before the Rookie Course started, I went to a neighbouring canton to buy derby gear so I could practice. Practice and hope to attain a minimal competency such that I would not be so horribly bruised again, so quickly. Roller derby gear purchased in Switzerland is pretty expensive. My knee pads &lt;em&gt;alone&lt;/em&gt; cost 100 francs. But I have a job and a single yoga lesson here costs at least 20 CHF so I can deal with it. And those pads make falling forwards painless, which I rate quite highly. One must remember to fall &lt;em&gt;forward&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An expedition was undertaken to find a location suitable for practice. Such a location must be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;flat, ideally completely flat, oh god a single stone will kill me dead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;safely enclosed from roads, traffic, hills, chasms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;devoid of other people, with their beady, judging eyes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And another thing I did not even think to think about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;of a surface appropriate for the wheels on my skates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that the wheels which came with the 'starter' skates I got (Riedell R3s) are of a hardness appropriate for concrete and other hard-ish surfaces. (They're Sonar Flat Out wheels, with a hardness of 88A, for reference.) The indoor multi-purpose court we found at our university's sports centre fulfills the first three conditions, to an extent. There are people on exercise machines overlooking the court, but I can deal with judgement better than I can deal with skating into traffic and dying. It fails badly on the last condition. It has some kind of rubberized surface (you can leave small impressions in it with your nails) and when I first put on my skates and tried it out, something felt... wrong. I could stand upright with no effort to stay in one place. I could roll to a graceful stop by ceasing movement. When I tried to move forwards, my feet lagged strangely, and made me stumble. I could jump without filling with abject terror. Something was &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt;. I went home and did some research ('why roller skate sticky') and deduced that my wheels were responsible. For a surface that soft you need harder wheels to compensate, and my 88As wouldn't cut it. So I went off and bought some 95A hardness wheels and they seemed &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt;, not &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; but good enough because I'm not made of money or willingness to spend a morning going to Aarau, as pretty as their &lt;a href="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/62/Flag_of_Canton_of_Aargau.svg/220px-Flag_of_Canton_of_Aargau.svg.png"&gt;cantonal flag&lt;/a&gt; may be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minor logistical issues aside, I managed a tiny bit of practice before the first training session. It's hard to know how much worse I would have been without it. I was bad, real bad. I fell (backwards or otherwise messily) five times. While trying to do a T-stop I messed up somehow and twisted my ankle in a way that seems like something should have broken. My issue was mostly corners. I was trying to stay on the inside of the track to avoid being in the way of the others, who are much better than me (they are mostly more experienced, so this is natural). I can deal with hurting myself but I don't want to cause someone else to fall. The inside of the track has a tigher corner however, so I kept getting off balance. Obvious solution is to stop hugging the inside of the track. Or learn how to turn (coming soon!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the session we did a practice '27 in 5' (part of the minimal skills test is to skate 27 laps in 5 minutes) and I did &lt;em&gt;twelve&lt;/em&gt; laps in five minutes. That's awful. So bad. Much slow ... &lt;em&gt;but&lt;/em&gt; I was intentionally avoiding gaining speed on the straights because I had no idea how to deal with it on the corners, and I &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; didn't want to make someone else fall while they were trying to go fast. Especially not if it involves them falling on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also covered plow stops, which I find a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; easier and less ankle-destroying than T-stops, probably because I can keep both feet on the ground. Overall though, my favourite stopping method is 'falling and curling up in a ball'. Fall small, they say. Be grand, they say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was alarmed at first by the horrible disparity in skill level at the Rookie course. Some people were doing &lt;em&gt;crossovers&lt;/em&gt; in week 1. I mistakenly tried to keep up and got several days of hobbling around the office as my reward. I resolved to practice (once my leg regained full function) and &lt;em&gt;definitely catch up&lt;/em&gt;, because that is &lt;em&gt;definitely possible&lt;/em&gt; in a week (spoiler: no).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now for some thoughts on skill-acquisition. At this point, being on skates feels terrifying. The ground moves perilously beneath me at every moment. Even staying still requires intense and tiresome muscle activity. My whole body is inexplicably involved in the task of not falling to my doom. I imagine however that this is how cycling felt, once. On cycling: I am a good cyclist. I am not an &lt;em&gt;advanced&lt;/em&gt; cyclist: there are many things I can't do. I can't swing my leg over my bike and jump off while I'm slowing down, and I can't cycle stably with no hands. I can't turn really sharply. I don't try to do these things. I am good at the things I choose to do (causal direction left as exercise for the reader). I feel utterly comfortable on my bike - it is an extension of me, and I can go where I desire without consciously acting. It would be hard for me to explain exactly how I cycle, because so much of it is automatic. My hope and belief is that this is how experienced people feel on rollerskates. Until then, I can't &lt;em&gt;play&lt;/em&gt; while on skates, because I am far too occupied with questions of basic mechanics. I want to get to the stage where I can think more about what I'm doing and less about &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; I'm doing it. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="roller derby"></category><category term="cycling"></category></entry><entry><title>roller derby week 0</title><link href="/life/2016-08-28-roller-derby-0.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-08-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>corcra</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-08-28:/life/2016-08-28-roller-derby-0.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In a turn of events baffling to those who know me, I decided to sign up to (try to) learn to play roller derby. Roller derby is a full-contact sport played on rollerskates. The game basically consists of getting in someone's way, or getting through people who are getting in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In a turn of events baffling to those who know me, I decided to sign up to (try to) learn to play roller derby. Roller derby is a full-contact sport played on rollerskates. The game basically consists of getting in someone's way, or getting through people who are getting in your way. It's like 'walking through Times Square' but on rollerskates and the pushing is consensual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My interest in the sport is incredibly out of character. I'm not a fan of falling over. I don't like getting hurt. I don't really like doing things which might hurt others, and while I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; enjoy the sensation of moving quickly, it also terrifies me. I appear to lack any thrill-seeking bones and I've always been fine with that. Why would I do something &lt;em&gt;dangerous&lt;/em&gt;? Also, and this is not unrelated, I'm &lt;em&gt;sort&lt;/em&gt; of small.  I'm 161cm (5'3") tall and weigh about 55kg (120lb). In a game of momentum transfer, I am going to lose. I fare a lot better at academic pursuits, like writing code while slowly horizontalising myself, or drawing amorphous manifolds on whiteboards. Also computer games. I got an accidental headshot in Overwatch last night, so you could say I'm pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I also moved to a new country (Switzerland) recently, and having one's non-work life unceremoniously deleted is a good opportunity to find new hobbies. (Or rediscover old ones, like competitive online video games) I had been aware of roller derby for some time because a former flatmate was involved with the Dublin Roller Girls back when we lived together in 2010. At the time I wasn't interested in the idea of sports, much less &lt;em&gt;violent&lt;/em&gt; ones, so I never seriously considered the idea of doing it. Also, I'm so small! I was in the 'too light to donate blood' category back then. However, now that I am older and wiser and excluded from blood-donation for different reasons, I have decided to get out of my comfort zone. Wildly. So far that traditional notions of distance can no longer be meaningfully used to describe the relative locations of roller derby and my comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, while scouting around for Things To Take Up in Zurich I found the &lt;a href="http://www.rollerderby.ch/"&gt;Zürich City RollerGirlz&lt;/a&gt;, noticed they had a try-out day and convinced my good friend and coworker Natalie to go with me. That was my first time ever on rollerskates. I fell twice on the same spot and had a bruise which lasted, visibly, for three weeks.  But it was fun and I learned that the game is more nuanced and less openly brutal than 'shove people, also you're on rollerskates'. There are rules. I knew in a sense that there would be, but I also feared that 'full contact' means anything goes. Thankfully not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Natalie and I signed up to the rookie course, and I intend to document my progress. Natalie has a video-camera too, so if we remember we might compile clips to make a sweet training montage video at the end. It lasts 12 weeks and culminates in the Minimal Skills Test required to be eligible to actually play roller derby. It seems implausible to me that I can go from &lt;em&gt;never having skated&lt;/em&gt; to passing that test in a 12 week period (while also doing a PhD and becoming a professional Overwatch player), but time shall tell. I'm quite motivated to try, because everyone loves underdog stories, and I really like having things to care about that &lt;em&gt;aren't&lt;/em&gt; related to my PhD. File this under coping mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The course actually started two weeks ago, I just didn't think to blog about it until now. I was searching for things like 'how to roller skate' and came across some really useful and reassuring blog posts from other beginners (or ex-beginners), and realised how much I value reading about other people sucking at things. So here I am, sucking at a thing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="roller derby"></category><category term="moving"></category><category term="overwatch"></category></entry><entry><title>play me a match of doto for your heart</title><link href="/life/2016-06-11-play-me-a-match-of-doto-for-your-heart.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-06-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>corcra</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-06-11:/life/2016-06-11-play-me-a-match-of-doto-for-your-heart.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here are some strange messages I have received on OKCupid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;???&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you are evil // Sorry you do not you're Sorry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hi // how are you? // what did you mean with that you are dog person&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hi. How are you? Please I need a favor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hey bitch, are you studying computer science? &lt;em&gt;(this …&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here are some strange messages I have received on OKCupid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;???&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you are evil // Sorry you do not you're Sorry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hi // how are you? // what did you mean with that you are dog person&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hi. How are you? Please I need a favor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hey bitch, are you studying computer science? &lt;em&gt;(this is probably the
    closest thing to 'abuse' I have received on the site)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I love dogs tho&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All of which are American dreams comrade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MY GOD YOU HAVE A FACE // Sorry, was that rude? Is it rude to tell a
    woman she has a face?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;people respond to my profile&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The context here is that I write very small pieces of speculative
fiction in the 'explanation' box for my questions. Someone asked if they
were Cormac McCarthy quotes once, which may be my greatest achievement.
I've also gotten a few messages written in the same style as my
responses. Dating site as platform for collaborative fiction-writing,
anyone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I could not and still can not tell if your page is a real dating
    profile or just a place to either copy and paste or write original
    satire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have an incredible amount of respect for your commitment to
    this bit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;five stars for FUCKING TERRIFYING OH MY GODDDDDDDDDDDD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;are you a Turing test?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;play me a match of doto for your heart &lt;em&gt;(amazing)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ayyy gurl, no need to get a BKB cuz my love is pure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never change, internet.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="lol"></category><category term="dating"></category><category term="dota"></category></entry></feed>