<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>apeirotope - meta</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/atom/meta.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2021-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>redesign</title><link href="/meta/2021-01-04-redesign.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>corcra</name></author><id>tag:None,2021-01-04:/meta/2021-01-04-redesign.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have updated the design of the website! This started off as 'drop in a new Pelican theme and be done' and grew into a micro-project to do while confined to my parents house over Christmas (pandemic etc). I also watched lots of medium-to-terrible TV (GYNOTOPIA, SERIOUSLY?), which is a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have updated the design of the website! This started off as 'drop in a new Pelican theme and be done' and grew into a micro-project to do while confined to my parents house over Christmas (pandemic etc). I also watched lots of medium-to-terrible TV (GYNOTOPIA, SERIOUSLY?), which is a good accompaniment to making tiny tweaks in CSS and seeing what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For posterity, the previous version of apeirotope looked like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2021/apeirotope_medius_index.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... which was an edited version of the &lt;a href="https://github.com/onur/medius"&gt;medius theme&lt;/a&gt;, which was designed to imitate Medium. Post example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2021/apeirotope_medius_post.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new version, also for posterity (the internet is a flimsy place for memories) looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2021/apeirotope_voce_index.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2021/apeirotope_voce_post.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new design is a modified version of the &lt;a href="https://github.com/limbenjamin/voce"&gt;voce theme&lt;/a&gt; - my fork is &lt;a href="https://github.com/corcra/voce"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. You can do a diff between my fork and the original one for the most comprehensive account of the edits I made, but I'll describe them in English here. Also, for comparison, here's what apeirotope would look like in mostly-plain voce:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2021/apeirotope_voce_index_original.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not really a fair comparison because the voce theme uses tags carefully and sparingly, whereas I use them freely, and instead use categories (which it doesn't really use) to categorise my posts. You can see a much better version of the voce theme on its &lt;a href="https://limbenjamin.com/"&gt;creator's personal page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Particular edits I made:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obviously, get rid of the milieu of tags. I experimented with replacing them with my categories, but I didn't like the result. I settled with fully removing that section, and adding pages for Tags and Categories to the navigation bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removing more elements, I got rid of the "logo" area and (not shown) the copyright stuff at the bottom. As far as I can tell from 10s of searching, those types of copyright declarations are mostly for scaring people off plagiarising your stuff, but aren't actually necessary to legally assert copyright. Following up with a further 20s of searching, I'd probably put a CC-BY-SA license on this site if I had to. I haven't had any legal issues in the 5 years or so I've had the website, so maybe copyright will be abolished soon and I won't need to think further about this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It looks like I added an italic serif font, but he (Benjamin Lin, voce creator) seems to have done a nontrivial style update &lt;em&gt;four days ago&lt;/em&gt;, which included removing it. This is funny to me because the previous update was in April, so I guess we were both spending part of our new years time editing the voce design. Hi Benjamin!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's ideally not visible at all, but I ripped out a bunch of surveillance-flavoured internals, including: anything to do with google analytics, and (hopefully) all calls to external sources, including fonts, bootstrap CSS, etc. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/corcra/status/1342171321472573442"&gt;Webfonts are hosted locally for apeirotope&lt;/a&gt;. Possibly didn't catch everything and maybe my website is slower now because a weak little OVH VPS is serving everything. My guess is that this site doesn't do enough traffic for that to be a real concern, but given the lack of analytics/me bothering to look at nginx logs ever, I have no idea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introducing my "colour-coding categories" nonsense (which I already had in medius, but required rejigging given the new templates in voce). This was probably the most complicated part because I &lt;em&gt;sort of&lt;/em&gt; understand CSS, but not well enough to readily diagnose why certain styles are overriding each other. Concessions had to be made, but I am fairly happy with the result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Directly edited minified bootstrap CSS to remove a weird navy colour that kept appearing in my unflavoured links. Numerous other minor style edits, including removing that (admittedly lovely) turquoise colour, and making things generally smaller.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tags page sorts by number of posts, not alphabetically. Nobody should look at the tags page, though. I have a link-rot issue where I don't want to modify &lt;em&gt;categories&lt;/em&gt; (since they define absolute paths to posts), but it's open season on tags and some day I may do a pass on de-duplicating them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The archives page (new!) only segregates posts by month if there are more than 4 in a year. I am most proud of this edit because it required writing some Jinja, which first required learning the word "Jinja" so as to upgrade my search queries from "if statement pelican".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, this was NOT procrastination from generating other types of content for the website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="webdev"></category><category term="css"></category></entry><entry><title>new site for research</title><link href="/meta/2020-11-05-new-site.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>corcra</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-11-05:/meta/2020-11-05-new-site.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I made this tweet several months ago:
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/_hylandSL/status/1269620384908836865"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2020/research_website.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(This website is now an elaborate mechanism for me to retweet myself.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory apeiroto.pe counts as a personal research page, but it's not of the "glorified CV" variety I was thinking about when I wrote the tweet.
When I started apeiroto …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I made this tweet several months ago:
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/_hylandSL/status/1269620384908836865"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2020/research_website.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(This website is now an elaborate mechanism for me to retweet myself.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory apeiroto.pe counts as a personal research page, but it's not of the "glorified CV" variety I was thinking about when I wrote the tweet.
When I started apeiroto.pe I liked the idea of being unashamedly &lt;em&gt;multifaceted&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apeirotope"&gt;get it?&lt;/a&gt;), and I still do. But for the sake of those people who are only interseted in the facets of me which pertain to research, &lt;strong&gt;I've created a dedicated research-facing website: &lt;a href="https://sthy.land"&gt;sthy.land&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's very sparse, and I don't 100% love the theme (it is of course also using Pelican), but it's good enough for now. Correspondingly, the "research" page on apeiroto.pe will link there from now on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sort of post is usually accompanied by a promise to update more often. I refuse to make such a promise.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="pelican"></category><category term="webdev"></category><category term="research"></category></entry><entry><title>important site updates</title><link href="/meta/2016-07-06-important-site-update.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-07-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>corcra</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-07-06:/meta/2016-07-06-important-site-update.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two matters, one vastly more important than the other:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSL is active! It was incredibly easy to set up with &lt;a href="https://letsencrypt.org/"&gt;Let's Encrypt&lt;/a&gt;. Losing SSL was one sad thing about moving away from GitHub pages, but it is clearly remedied. Now you can access my content securely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This site has a …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two matters, one vastly more important than the other:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSL is active! It was incredibly easy to set up with &lt;a href="https://letsencrypt.org/"&gt;Let's Encrypt&lt;/a&gt;. Losing SSL was one sad thing about moving away from GitHub pages, but it is clearly remedied. Now you can access my content securely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This site has a new subdomain: &lt;a href="http://dog.apeiroto.pe/"&gt;http://dog.apeiroto.pe/&lt;/a&gt;. It shows a new dog gif/image on reload. SSL is... not working on the subdomain, I think I need to poke at nginx for that. You can now emulate friendship with me by hitting refresh on that page!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way I did the new image on reload thing is hacky so here goes: I considered trying to actually learn JavaScript and then remembered I had to go wash my horse. So I found a 'load random image on reload' script, which puls images from a list defined in the script. Given I want to just drop files in a folder and have them enter the pupper-rotation this was no good, so I wrote a script (in bash) to compile the contents of the dog-folder and stick that in the HTML. Easy. What I need to do now is combine the 'count puppers and update HTML' script with the 'sync puppers to web server' script and I'll be sorted. Or put both on cronjobs and forget about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing there are 210 such images. That's 2.1G of doggos. I regularly collect these pictures from twitter/imgur/giphy so it should grow slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming soon: cat.apeiroto.pe.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="dogs"></category><category term="gifs"></category><category term="ssl"></category><category term="encryption"></category></entry><entry><title>moved to pelican</title><link href="/meta/2016-05-17-moved-to-pelican.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-05-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>corcra</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-05-17:/meta/2016-05-17-moved-to-pelican.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's what happened:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My phone started acting up. The lock button turned into a 'maybe turn the phone off' button. The unlock button turned into a 'maybe turn the phone off, &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; open the camera?' button. I impulse-purchased a new phone, and the old one magically fixed itself. New phone …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's what happened:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My phone started acting up. The lock button turned into a 'maybe turn the phone off' button. The unlock button turned into a 'maybe turn the phone off, &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; open the camera?' button. I impulse-purchased a new phone, and the old one magically fixed itself. New phone went into a box and my SIM remained micro-sized for a little longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I moved to Switzerland, got a nano SIM, started dual-wielding phones. New phone for new SIM, old phone for everything else. I migrated my apps to new phone (this was surprisingly tricky and there's an entire story in there about me conveniently being in the USA to receive a single text message, but it's a tangent), so I got a new Signal fingerprint. (Then my old phone bricked itself, as they do.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to put my new Signal fingerprint on my lovely SSLy Github-pages website and noticed it was broken. For how long this was the case I don't know. I think it was a Jekyll update? Who knows. The time had come. I'd been thinking of leaving gh-pages for a while, so this was a good excuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reasons for wanting to leave:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using plugins with Jekyll and gh-pages is mildly painful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the solution, and/or Jekyll itself was &lt;em&gt;increasingly frustratingly slow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gh-pages was too mysterious&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and the new reason:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;website was mysteriously broken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are probably fixable, I am sure. Maybe my solution isn't the best, but it's mine. I decided to: &lt;strong&gt;move from Jekyll to &lt;a href="link to pelican"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;host my site myself&lt;/strong&gt;. By the time you're reading this, I'll have achieved that second part. At the time I'm writing it, I haven't even started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did I do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jekyll uses Ruby, Pelican uses Python, I know Python a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; better than Ruby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I never knew Jekyll very well, so there were no temptingly sunk costs to care about&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I saw a site using Pelican during an impressionable moment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;self-hosting (in a VPS, let's not be unreasonable) affords a level of control that I apparently want&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this site now looks &lt;em&gt;rather different&lt;/em&gt;. That's because another thing happened: I realised that I'm not a front-end web developer, or designer, or basically a person who has touched HTML since she was making Pokémon fansites as a ten-year-old. But I'd also like my site to look good. The old version, [which I should screenshot for posterity] was my first adventure into CSS and was unsurprisingly minimalist. I got some compliments on the design of it (yay!) but it was very hand-crafted and it looked it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I am balancing competing desires: a site which &lt;strong&gt;looks good&lt;/strong&gt; (and works well), and a site which is &lt;strong&gt;my creation&lt;/strong&gt;. The solution for now is to use an existing Pelican theme, made by someone who presumably knows a lot more about websiting than I do, and modify it to my own purposes. Apparently the one I picked was intended to look like &lt;a href="..."&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; so now after several hours of mucking around I have a Medium blog with no features. Excellent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm modifying the theme (see &lt;a href="https://github.com/corcra/medius"&gt;my fork&lt;/a&gt;) and I will continue to do so until I get distracted by &lt;a href="http://www.internationalphoneticalphabet.org/ipa-sounds/ipa-chart-with-sounds/"&gt;something else&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post brought to you by an internet outage at the AirBnB I currently live in.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="webdev"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="pelican"></category><category term="css"></category><category term="phone"></category><category term="so many tags why"></category><category term="IPA"></category></entry><entry><title>just the tips</title><link href="/meta/2015-05-20-just-the-tips.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-05-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>corcra</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-05-20:/meta/2015-05-20-just-the-tips.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For fear of turning this blog into a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_restaurant_process"&gt;Chinese Restaurant Process&lt;/a&gt; I've spawned a new category, called &lt;font class="tips"&gt;tips&lt;/font&gt;. This category is the closest to my original vision for a PhD-blog, where I would write down useful things as I learned them. It turns out that's not very sustainable (PhD involves …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For fear of turning this blog into a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_restaurant_process"&gt;Chinese Restaurant Process&lt;/a&gt; I've spawned a new category, called &lt;font class="tips"&gt;tips&lt;/font&gt;. This category is the closest to my original vision for a PhD-blog, where I would write down useful things as I learned them. It turns out that's not very sustainable (PhD involves a lot of learning). Every time I went to write a post I found it difficult to resist the urge to make it very comprehensive and pedagogical, which ended up in me carefully studying &lt;code&gt;man&lt;/code&gt; pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;font class="tips"&gt;tips&lt;/font&gt; category will contain posts that are unashamedly brief and perhaps shamefully trivial. If I have a simple problem that took me &lt;em&gt;too long&lt;/em&gt; (like  over 5 minutes) to solve, I'll put my solution in &lt;font class="tips"&gt;tips&lt;/font&gt;. As ever, making hard categorical assignments to soft things like blog posts containing multiple topics is a fool's errand, but I'll deal with it as it comes. Perhaps I should be using &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Latent_Dirichlet_allocation"&gt;LDA&lt;/a&gt;, or like, tags or something.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="categories"></category><category term="LDA"></category><category term="bayesian nonparametrics"></category><category term="webdev"></category></entry><entry><title>temporal anomaly</title><link href="/meta/2015-03-16-temporal-anomaly.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>corcra</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-03-16:/meta/2015-03-16-temporal-anomaly.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm gradually migrating old posts over from my &lt;a href="https://jackofalljacks.wordpress.com/"&gt;WordPress blog&lt;/a&gt;, which will be backdated, ruining the timestamps-through-commits system that could have been, but never was. Hopefully the validity of the alleged timestamps on these posts will never be important for anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparing the new post&lt;a href="#1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; with the old also …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm gradually migrating old posts over from my &lt;a href="https://jackofalljacks.wordpress.com/"&gt;WordPress blog&lt;/a&gt;, which will be backdated, ruining the timestamps-through-commits system that could have been, but never was. Hopefully the validity of the alleged timestamps on these posts will never be important for anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparing the new post&lt;a href="#1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; with the old also reminds me that Wordpress has competent web designers, words which cannot be applied to me. However, my blog has the advantage of working just as well(badly) without JavaScript, which is part of my decision to design it with &lt;a href="https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser.html.en"&gt;Tor Browser&lt;/a&gt; in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; At the time of writing this I had just migrated &lt;a href="{static}/2014-09-30-updating-shared-variables-in-theano.md" class="ml"&gt;"updating shared variables in theano"&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="wordpress"></category><category term="time travel"></category><category term="design"></category><category term="tor"></category><category term="webdev"></category></entry><entry><title>first post</title><link href="/meta/2015-01-26-first-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>corcra</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-01-26:/meta/2015-01-26-first-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Does anyone remember their first website? I know I was a nine-year-old with Microsoft Word and "Save as HTML", which seems like a decent reason to forget it, even if it was Pokemon-themed. Given my complete lack of gainful employment at the time, I took to website-making as if it …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Does anyone remember their first website? I know I was a nine-year-old with Microsoft Word and "Save as HTML", which seems like a decent reason to forget it, even if it was Pokemon-themed. Given my complete lack of gainful employment at the time, I took to website-making as if it were important, as if its utility would not soon be eclipsed by the simplicity afforded by services like Livejournal and Bebo&lt;a href="#1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;. I spent many hours refining and redefining my vision, a vision comprised mostly of iframes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here comes one now:
&lt;a href="http://media.ccc.de/browse/congress/2014/31c3_-_6373_-_en_-_saal_6_-_201412291600_-_the_only_thing_we_know_about_cyberspace_is_that_its_640x480_-_olia_lialina.html"&gt;The Only Thing We Know About Cyberspace Is That Its 640x480 (Olia Lialina @31C3)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="670" height="380" src="http://media.ccc.de/browse/congress/2014/31c3_-_6373_-_en_-_saal_6_-_201412291600_-_the_only_thing_we_know_about_cyberspace_is_that_its_640x480_-_olia_lialina/oembed.html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk is largely about the GeoCities era of personal websites, which was already on the way out when I was getting started, but things were different in Ireland anyway. We had 'Ireland On-Line', which is now a five-line &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ireland_On-Line"&gt;Wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt;, a legacy webmail service and a mausoleum of personal pages and auto-redirects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selected snippets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;optimised for Netscape 4.70&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.iol.ie/~taeger/"&gt;[source]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://www.iol.ie/~gscoil/images/netgaeilge.gif'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;What's cool: Gameboy, playstation, me, Doom.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.iol.ie/~gscoil/darlingtons/zac/index.htm"&gt;[source]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;While as yet, SnoopDos exists only on the Amiga, I'm happy to report that similar utilities have sprung up for DOS, Windows 3.1, Windows 95, and Windows NT. &lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.iol.ie/~ecarroll/snoopdos.html"&gt;[source]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Divorce, in the Church's view, threatens to deconstruct the primary unit upon which the model for the Church is built. The battle for the retention of the form of the traditional family becomes the battle for the retention of a particular model of church organisation. This is why the debate is so fiercely fought.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href="#2"&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.iol.ie/~mazzoldi/toolsforchange/zine/sam94/divorce.html"&gt;[source]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;"'Yo motherfucker,' Marx greeted. Proudhon was at a loss."&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.iol.ie/~mazzoldi/toolsforchange/marx/marx7.html"&gt;[source]&lt;/a&gt; (somehow related to previous one)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The genesis of a new British police force can be seen in Mowlam's proposal to introduce the subtitle 'Northern Ireland Police Service' (NIPS) to the RUC.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href="#3"&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="iol.ie/~saoirse/iris/1997/225.htm"&gt;[source]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cutting that unexpectedly-engrossing tangent short, I'll clarify that this site is not a nostalgia trip. I will be keeping the animated gifs to a minimum (unless they come from &lt;a href="http://beesandbombs.tumblr.com/"&gt;David Whyte&lt;/a&gt;) and attempting to adhere to sane design principles. The talk I linked planted a seed of sorts in me, though. I can't argue that it caused this site, because it's been in the works for a while, but it catalysed me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The seed is roughly this: In a time when one's internet presence was a deliberate act rather than a social necessity, making a website and appearing on cyberspace&lt;a href="#4"&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; was preceded by a question of surprisingly existential nature: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;"What will I make my website about? What do I have to say?"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that one's web presence today has similar associated questions (notably "what image do I wish to portray?"), but thanks to the existence of a set of well-established social norms, a person can largely ignore them. It is entirely possible to exist online without asking any existentalist questions. This is arguably great, because the internet is fantastic and should not be restricted to a set of people who find it necessary to frame their actions as manifestations of the struggle for self-definition, and/or people who know HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I fall somewhere in the 'and' category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm making a website for a few reasons, which are secretly the same reason&lt;a href="#5"&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;. I like thinking about what I have to say. I think questions of that nature are interesting and can be quite personally fulfilling, even if the answer turns out to be 'mostly nothing'. I also like thinking about how to say things, which is part of the reason this entry has taken me far too long to finish&lt;a href="#6"&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also the careful deliberateness which goes into creating a website like this. My CSS was completely nonexistent when I started this a few weeks ago.  I'd recommend against reading the source code if you are sensitive about CSS, because terrible, likely-forbidden things have happened and I am remorseless. Things will only get worse as I enact my weird design plans on other parts of the site&lt;a href="#7"&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;. I cannot wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah, I could run a blog on an existing service, but where would be the fun in that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; Bebo became extremely popular in Ireland when I was about 15, and suddenly using the internet became socially acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="2"&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; I think this is particularly interesting, because Ireland finds itself (a mere 20 years later) on the precipice of another historic referendum (this time to legalise gay marriage), but the church makes the same old arguments. Society marches ever onwards, and the church is immobile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="3"&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; They went with PSNI in the end, presumably in deference to &lt;a href="http://nips.cc/"&gt;NIPS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="4"&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; Before it became infested with cybercriminals and c y b  e    r w a r  f   a     r        e.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="5"&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; Proof left as exercise to the reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="6"&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; Also fighting a losing battle against pre-ironic post-irony creeping into my tone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="7"&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; I intend to keep the blog as minimalist as is palatable.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="ccc"></category><category term="webdev"></category><category term="nostalgia"></category></entry></feed>